{
    "id": "7c1feed8f521455a9d2e5f88354e7e36",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I knew she ......................... arrive before long.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we will need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "may"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "96626dc685dc4dc591cb61f284b7b212"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will call you when I ............................... ready.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "am",
                "was"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "26fbd8ebd8f54b53a808064712544809"
        },
        {
            "question": "It ................................. before long.",
            "description": "We do not normally use the present continuous to make predictions about events that are outside peopleâ€™s control.",
            "answers": [
                "is raining",
                "is going to rain",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "18d75e8831fd42b2993323e03f7b6e3b"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ............................... cricket in my garden.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "are not playing",
                "are not going to play",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e8f0c76c170e4e20a4a60814dee070c7"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ................................. a new car next month.",
            "description": "Both the present continuous and going to can be used to talk about future events that are already planned. ",
            "answers": [
                "are getting",
                "are going to get",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "31f0fc0a0c57443487fcc3d7ccbbda9b"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ................................... here since July.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect continuous tense to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "is working",
                "has been working",
                "had worked"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a12863cf8b53452eb5c5a93f5d268e77"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ...................................... my wallet at home.",
            "description": "We normally use the present perfect tense to talk about finished events when there is no time reference. The simple past is also possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "had left",
                "left",
                "have left"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f24117ed9dd1414baa768057ff570b7f"
        },
        {
            "question": "It would be nice if you ................................... me a bit with the housework.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "help",
                "helped",
                "will help",
                "had helped"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "67f83c533c6f45d5ab538b29e49b1af7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Hardly had I arrived when trouble ................................",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we will need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "started",
                "start",
                "would start"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b1d6d04dc57b4bcdb5dc0b433a033b9a"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long ................................... a doctor?",
            "description": "We often use the present perfect to talk about how long present situations have lasted.",
            "answers": [
                "are you",
                "have you been",
                "were you"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "560f819992cc45eab1df4ee76831d59d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have ................................................... in this city for ten years.",
            "description": "The present perfect and the present perfect continuous can both be used to talk about actions and situations that started in the past and have continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "lived",
                "been living",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "da45268ae46a485493ee43f3c7d67ee4"
        },
        {
            "question": "One day scientists .......................................................... to find a cure for cancer.",
            "description": "We often use 'will be able to' to talk about future possibility and ability. ",
            "answers": [
                "be able to",
                "can",
                "will be able",
                "are able to"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "07406885f9aa43e4a73c89399a491599"
        }
    ]
}